Last week on Road to Avonlea.
Sarah Stanley, how dare you humiliate me
in there? You are a horrible old woman.
You don't have an ounce of respect for
my feelings.
Connor, did you see that dress? You got
damn problems. You two look like
sisters. You think so? Sarah, you can't.
To which places?
Sarah Stanley.
Let me come with you.
This is wrong! Right, Sarah!
Joan Pitts.
I've got a score to settle with you.
Where do you think you're going, huh?
Let me go.
Buck. Take your hands off. Buck. Come
on, come here.
Trying to give us the slip.
Don't play games with us, Joe Pitts. I
want it back, Joe.
Every penny.
But I never stole anything.
And I am not Joe Pitts.
I am Sarah Stanley, and I ran away. It's
the truth.
Now, why won't you believe me?
I don't know who you are or what you're
talking about.
You remember me now, Jill Pitts?
Give me my money!
I'm not who you think I am. You're
making Buck real mad.
Yeah. You're gonna pay back what you
stole from me.
You're gonna pick every pocket on the
wharf, you hear me?
Pockets? Do you hear me?
Yes, I hear you.
And you're gonna turn every dime of it
over to me, understood?
I bet she's got a stash hit on her right
now.
Abel will be glad to see that.
Right. We'll board up that window. Good
this time.
my son.
You got to keep your strength up.
Now,
is
that how you treats your old man?
And you not seeing me for such a long
while?
I wouldn't come to you if you withdrawn
your dying breath.
in flesh and blood.
Well, you almost got your wish when I
fell off in that lighthouse at Avonlea
the briny.
But I tricked you again. I come back.
Here, look.
See? A crane. He left me a souvenir.
Pretty, ain't it?
It's vengeance, I swore, and it's
vengeance I'll get.
You leads me to Ezekiel Crane and the
treasure what he's got hidden.
I ain't leading you no place.
Cotton Crane's a friend of mine, and I
ain't betraying him for the likes of
All right.
You'll tell me where he's hiding.
Because if you don't tell me, you won't
tell nobody.
It's the strangest thing. First my
silver sugar tongs went missing, then
bowl. I know I left them right on the
table after supper.
My watch was pinned to my jacket. Now
it's missing as well. I hear tell that
Rachel Lynn's double damas tablecloth
just disappeared off the clothesline.
She's madder than a wet hen.
Well, we're not safe in our beds.
Never thought I'd see today we'd have to
lock our doors in Avonlea.
Sarah. Quick, say hello. It's Aunt
Olivia. Hello,
Aunt Olivia.
So many answers.
Can't keep them straight.
Well, you don't have that many, Sarah.
No, she's just joking, Aunt Olivia.
She was.
Oh, don't give it a thought, Olivia.
Felix is always telling bad jokes. Hey,
Felicity.
The worst.
And he isn't the least bit funny. You
just have to grin and bear it until they
grow out of it. Come on.
We are all weak vessels.
We encounter various trials as we travel
the road of our lives.
We fall into the valley of temptation
and we are sorely pried.
James... Don't he ever stop? My bum's
getting... I am being tempted by God.
Each and every one of us is tempted by
his or her own lust.
Give me one more poke in the ribs and
I'm going to felt you one.
Death.
Not the death of our bodies.
But the death of that which is far more
important.
The death of our souls.
I don't know what's gotten into that
girl.
Oh, they all go through it, believe me.
Where is Sarah anyway?
I'll find her.
Excuse me.
Put it back, Joe.
Bye.
You at Slowing Circle. Bye.
Hello. Felix!
Janet.
I don't know how this happened, but with
Felix's health, the money from the
collection plate has ended up in the
children's possession.
I beg your pardon, but what do you mean
with Felix's help?
You don't think Sarah thought it up on
her own, do you?
Well, if she's so disobedient as you say
she is, then... Yes, I do.
Return this money to Reverend Leonard.
Go on, now. Both of you. Go on.
In my opinion, Janet King, Felix is a
bad influence on Sarah.
I think it best they don't play together
anymore.
Well, I think it's the other way around.
I think Sarah eggs him on, but if that's
the way you feel, it shoots me fine.
Sarah, Felix.
Sarah, come on, let's go. We're not
staying there. We're not wanted.
Quit dragging your feet.
Come on. The boss wants us. Let me go.
Buck Hogan. And Joe Pitt.
Found her.
You should have kept running, Joe Pitts.
Friends what runs from us ain't friends
no more.
She brung you this to make up for lost
time.
That all of it? For starters.
Ain't that right, Joe?
Speak up. The boss has been talking to
you.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Sir, is it?
So, you learned respect for your elders
since you flew the coop. I
likes respect.
You runs away from us again and you'll
wind up in the boneyard.
Now, get her out of my sight and don't
come back till she's paid in full.
What you doing with that cat?
What's she to you?
I got a score to settle with her.
Oh, you don't say. And I got a score to
settle with that thief, Captain Crane.
Captain Crane ain't no thief.
Now, you ain't seen none of that
treasure, have you, boy?
Now, why don't you tell me where he is?
I want what's mine, Pa.
And I want that kid.
Where is he?
Crane won't talk to nobody but me.
And you know that.
Captain Crane's in Jamaica.
Jamaica.
And don't you give me no trouble, boy.
None, Pa.
Never in the entire history of the
King's family has there been a thief.
Say, Hedy, I don't know where you caught
me red -handed.
I know it don't look good, but I, uh...
It doesn't look good.
That's right. Don't look good.
Thing is, you're right.
Whatever way you're thinking.
Well, that's just it.
I can't really hardly think at all. It
hurts so much.
What hurts, child?
My head and all.
Your head?
Inside. Hurt some fierce.
Oh, good Lord.
You really aren't well, then.
You sick?
Oh, yeah, sick.
Sick as a dog.
I've been too hard on you.
You've been hard as nails.
Oh, Sarah, dear.
Maybe too late, you know.
I'm bound for the River Jordan.
I'm damaged straight through and out the
bottom.
That's what the voices tell me.
Voices?
Voices. Do you want some time ahead?
Don't you ever hear no voices?
No. Oh, Lord.
Oh, you poor dear child.
How long have you been hearing these
voices?
Since I had the fever.
I must have pushed you too hard.
I must have.
Oh, Sarah dear.
Can you ever forgive me?
Sure. I forgive you.
So, uh, what's for supper?
Whatever your heart desires, my dear.
I'll have cake.
Cake?
Can I take the... Of course you can have
cake.
I'll make it right away.
Now, you just sit there and rest
quietly.
Don't you worry about a thing. I'll just
make a cake.
Chocolate.
Felix,
I want the truth. Who took that money?
Was it you?
No, it wasn't me.
Well, if it wasn't you, it wasn't Sarah.
It wasn't exactly Sarah.
Well, who was it then?
I'm speaking to you, young man.
I never... Until I hear the truth, Felix
King, it's bread and milk for supper
for you.
cold and give his eyes deep, lay his
hands on him.
What do you think you're doing, young
lady?
I'm cleaning the silver.
Isn't it in the middle of the night?
Sir, the voice made me do it.
I'm laying in bed, mouth snuggled up
tight, and all of a sudden I hear, get
and clean the silver.
Get up and clean it.
Crazy dumb witzes.
Now, now, Sarah.
Don't excite yourself now.
Just leave the silver where it is, dear.
Go on to bed.
Go on.
Bye.
Kevin, you're here.
Kathy, are you all right?
What on earth is going on up there?
Sarah, she's just having a, having a,
having a fit.
I had to lock her in a room last night.
She got up to polish the silver.
Well? At midnight.
That's just plain crazy.
She's demented.
Here's the voices.
Voices?
Sounds like she's turned into a raving
lunatic.
We do.
There's never been a hint of lunacy in
the King family.
There has not.
This is terrible.
It's a disaster.
Now what?
I don't know, but let's not wait to find
out.
Remember, careful.
Don't be too hard on a child not right
in the head. Remember.
Olivia.
Oh, my goodness. Look at this mess.
Oh, no.
Well, she can't get far.
Oh, pardon me.
I'm sorry. I'm quick.
We should have something terrible.
Go, Pitts.
Go earn your cake before I strangle you
myself.
He jumped right out in front of me.
Look at my apples.
Finally gotcha.
Joe Pets.
What are we going to do? We keep her in
there forever?
Why not?
Let me out!
Why don't we put her in a room and take
turns watching her, a vigil night and
day? And hot bath.
A hot bath followed by ice cold. Or is
it cold followed by hot? Or how about a
big dose of castor oil to clean her out?
Or, oh, Hattie, that tonic. The one
twice a day settles the nerves. Oh, no,
ladies, we're deluding ourselves.
Tonic won't settle that child down.
She's a rape.
and a specialist from the city.
Special? I don't believe in specialists.
I tell you what's wrong with your right
nostril. No, nothing about the left. No,
not a specialist. No, no, no, not that
kind of specialist. I mean one of those
newfangled head doctors who've talked
some sense into her. Oh, Janet, she'll
talk wings around any specialist.
There's only really one thing we can do.
All this private between us.
And there is our niece. We owe that much
to her celebrity.
made up my mind.
I've got the letter out of the bed. Oh,
no. No choice.
From now on, we handle Sarah Stanley
with kindness and... Betty, what if it
doesn't work?
I am still the eldest, Olivia, and what
I say still goes.
From now on...
Here's where you'll both stay under lock
and key till we're safe and sound in
Jamaica. When the wind blows off there,
Captain.
Good.
I'm sorry, Sarah.
Are you all right?
Yes, but I don't understand.
I had to get you away from them.
But it looks like I got us into bigger
trouble.
This has gone from bad to worse.
Running away was a pretty silly thing to
do.
I should have never let you. It wasn't
your fault.
Yeah.
Sarah.
Do you think you could squeeze through
here?
I don't know. Let me try.
Now, if you get out there, you keep
going, you hear me?
What about you?
Don't you worry about me. I'll be okay.
The hospital needs me for a while.
We'll be all right.
Don't worry. The doc's right there.
You be careful.
Go, don't worry.
Move away.
Hurry.
No, that... Hurry. Maybe we'll catch a
knife. Come on.
You all right?
Here.
Let's get another chili.
I'll get it.
I thought that lady looked so good.
Excuse me, Sarah?
After you finish your breakfast... Oh,
I'm not rushing you now, of course.
No, no, I mean, you take as long as you
wish, you know.
I just wondered if perhaps you might
like to...
Tidier room?
No.
Oh, fine, fine, fine.
Oh, it's absolutely fine.
Don't get upset now.
Not that you have to do anything.
Just sit there and twiddle your thumbs,
if that's what you want.
Hey, old man, hey.
Won't you say we go on a picnic?
Maybe.
Of course.
Oh, wonderful.
Who would you like to invite, Sarah?
Felicity? No, no.
Just me and you.
Oh, what a lovely idea.
You and I on a picnic.
Oh, Sarah, I do believe you're on the
men and girls.
My, my.
I'd say this is the nicest time we've
spent together in days.
Um, pickled pink, you suggested.
It's better than a bloody kick in the
bum, ain't it?
Sarah?
The island's over there, dear. On the
other side.
No, it ain't.
It's over there. Can't you see it?
Sparkling like a beautiful jewel on the
water.
Oh, yes, of course, dear.
Now, what do you say if we have our
picnic in China?
Wherever you like, of course.
But, you know, Hera, I do think you
might try rowing a
little to the left.
Isn't that a nice idea?
Nope.
Uh, Sarah?
Ain't you having a good time now at
Hattie's?
I know.
What if I roll for a while?
I kind of like rolling.
But if you really want to at Hattie's.
Oh, I do. I do, dear. I really do.
We have to trade places, you know.
Yes. Right.
Oh.
Don't do that.
Don't do that, Harry.
told us they locked you in the outhouse
yesterday?
Yeah, a bunch of old hags, a lot of
them.
Look, Joe, I think this whole thing has
gone too far.
I mean, you've got everyone thinking
Sarah's crazy and Aunt Hattie's in a
tizzy. You don't have to worry about her
no more.
How come?
I just drowned the old fat.
Oh, dear, she hasn't been herself for
days.
Well, is she?
Hold her.
Have her committed.
Have myself committed.
I
hope
we'll leave quite halfway to Jamaica by
now.
Thank you kindly.
Appreciate it.
I never thought I'd see Avonlea again.
Come with me?
Nope.
After leaving a pickpocket with your
Aunt Hattie, you're going to have to
yourself.
I know.
I don't have the brains God gave geese.
Me neither, I guess.
Should have never let you come with me.
Guess we've both been kind of stupid.
Thanks, Gus Pike.
Aunt Hattie?
Aunt Hattie, where are you?
All right.
I'll get you warm and dry it off. Close
the door, darling. There we go.
Aunt Hattie!
Aunt Janet, Felix.
So nice to see you.
No, no. Don't let her near me.
Sarah. No, don't get her worked up. She
could be dangerous.
We just stumbled across Aunt Hattie
dripping wet.
Can you imagine such a thing?
I don't know what you're talking about.
What has happened to the house?
Who made this mess?
Poor Aunt Hattie.
Gracious providence.
It looks like a tornado struck.
Aunt Hattie, you poor dear, let me get
you a blanket.
Get away from me.
Let her get away from me. She's up to
something. If you don't pipe down, I'm
going to have a conniption fit.
Don't get excited.
Aunt Hattie's upset.
You're upset.
Well, we're all upset.
So we'll just stand here calmly and
quietly
while I decide what to do.
But Aunt Janet, this is all a
misunderstanding.
I... Don't take it the wrong way,
dearest.
But you have lost your mind.
Cecil!
Are you Sarah or not?
Felix!
Sarah! Sarah Stanley!
Thought she was going home.
I am going home. This is your present
for my Aunt Hattie.
You ain't Sarah.
Oh!
You're Joe Pitts, ain't you? You
little... Go!
Let me go!
Get your bleeding hands off me! Let me
go!
You see, you thought she was me.
Who? The girl who looks like me. And who
might that be, Sarah?
See, she was pretending to be me, but
she didn't tell me who she really was.
Sarah, if you would just sit down,
perhaps... Don't make her nervous,
Lord knows what she'll do.
That's just the point, Aunt Hetty.
I'm not nervous.
Now, anyone would be confused if they
thought I was someone else, but I wasn't
here. And over there, they all thought I
was someone else, too.
I told you we should get a specialist
down here. They know what to do with
cases. If you would just let me finish,
Aunt Janet, I could explain everything.
You see, the other girl... We know,
dear.
They're both you.
No, no, no. You just think they're both
me, but they're not.
Although she's very dangerous. She never
told me. Oh, make her stop. Make her
stop. I can't stand it.
Go! Easy.
Oh, that does it.
Now I see two of them.
Must be a nightmare.
What's going on here?
Who are you? I'm me, Aunt Janet.
Who are you?
That there is Jo Pet.
She's the one that stole Sarah's dress.
I never stole nothing. I got it from the
poor box. I ain't stealing.
Felix and I met her one day.
And what exactly would you know about
all this, Felix King?
It wasn't really my idea.
Joe and I decided to trade places for a
few days.
What? I wanted to get back at you, Aunt
Hattie.
I didn't know what else to do. You were
always at me.
Oh, good Lord.
Do you have any idea how dangerous all
that was, Sarah?
My, my.
Buck and rat and Abe Pike.
My head's bursting from all this.
I missed you so much, Aunt Hetty.
I'm truly sorry I caused so much
trouble.
Well, I miss that old Sarah more than I
can tell you.
Oh, and I am very grateful to you.
Spike for bringing you home in one
piece.
I wish you'd all quit yakking and figure
out what you're going to do with me. I
know what I'd like to do with you, but
it's against the law.
Miss King, if you don't mind me sticking
my two cents word in, I'd like to say
something on Jo's behalf.
I can't think of a thing I'd say on her
behalf.
I'd lock her up and throw away the key.
I know it, but you gotta think.
She's had nothing and nobody in her
life.
Heck, if it weren't for Miss Kang, I
would know nothing by nothing.
Prison will only make her hard and mean.
Sending her back where she come from
ain't gonna help neither.
Uh -uh.
Come here.
You're a bad apple, Joe Pitts.
There's no doubt about it.
Oh, maybe Gus is right.
Maybe you need a regular life.
Regular meals.
Regular hours.
School. Yes.
A nice, clean place to live.
I know.
You can stay at Janet's.
I beg your pardon.
Sarah, go on upstairs, tidy yourself up,
and I'll take Joe with you.
Heaven's sake, keep your eye on her.
Yes, Aunt Hattie.
Yes, Aunt Hattie?
That's it? She asks and you go without
no lip or nothing?
What's the fun in that?
Come on.
How could you dream of suggesting that
little demon come and live in my house?
Let her stay with Olivia.
With me?
Oh, heavens.
Well, what would Jasper say?
I mean, he could handle anyone, but Joe
Pitts.
Oh, she can't stay here.
I'd love for that child to last a
lifetime, but you, Janet.
No, I am the eldest, and it's my
decision she stays with you over my dead
Now, see here, Hiddiken, you can't push
me around.
If that child moves into my house, we're
all moving out.
I have a bone to pick with you, Joe
Pitts.
When we switched places, you never
warned me about Buck Hogan and the
pickpocket.
How was I supposed to know where you was
going?
You never warned me about Hetty King,
either.
One doesn't seem so bad as the other.
They ain't.
Hetty's worse.
She was only trying to look after you.
Besides, you're so safe here. You have
nothing to worry about.
Stay here for a while.
Things might turn out differently this
time.
No.
I don't... I don't fit.
Here.
We made the bet on this in the first
place.
I figure I lost.
No.
You keep it.
Girls, we're waiting.
No dilly -dallying now.
Come on, Joe.
Don't hold your breath.
I ain't coming.
Don't dawdle now, Sarah.
Now, Hetty, remember what we said.
Well, yes, perfect, Olivia Dale. Thank
you very much.
Elvira Lawson, I've come to make a
return, if you don't mind.
Is there something the matter with it,
Hetty?
Yes, there is.
Come over here, Sarah.
Now, Sarah, you know my mind regarding
such periphery.
Elvira, I'm afraid that this pinafore is
completely unsuitable for a young
woman. So we'd like to see... That is,
Sarah would like to see
something altogether different.
Don't you agree, Sarah?
Well, actually, Aunt Hattie, there's
much to be said for a solid pinafore.
A young girl's mind's already safe.
I think the pinafore will be fine, Mrs.
Lawson.
Not the child.
The other drink.